<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>[ Y k N x ]</title>
    <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on [ Y k N x ]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 15:49:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//yknx4.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Database branches with Git Hooks</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/database-branches-with-git-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 15:49:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/database-branches-with-git-hooks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;You may skip to the solution part at the bottom if you feel brave&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branching means you diverge from the main line of development and continue to do work without messing with that main line. - &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Git-Branching-Branches-in-a-Nutshell&#34; title=&#34;3.1 Git Branching - Branches in a Nutshell&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branches are one of the more powerful features of a VCS, you can work on new features and test changes without touching your master code. But many times those changes implies to do some changes on the database too, and well, your database certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t live within your repository, so if you want to go back to master or to another branch you need to discard the changes you made to the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this you have many options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;Rails&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Rollback any migration you made&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop your db and create (or restore) a clean one &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;bye bye changes~&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup your current db and create (or restore a clean one) each time you switch branches so you have a standalone copy for each branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can see each of this options has it&amp;rsquo;s drawbacks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;Rails&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt; When you rollback your migrations you may lose any data that is not properly handled in the rollback, face the fact that some data is not easily recoverable or even worse, you may face the ugly and troublesome &lt;code&gt;ActiveRecord::IrreversibleMigration&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropping your db and creating a new one each time you need to switch to another branch can take a lot of time; specially when you have to download and import a production database dump with millions of records (&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on a project in which this process easily takes about 20~ minutes&lt;/em&gt;), besides that you also loses any changes you did in your branch, changes that may take some extra time to regenerate when you go back to the branch you where working on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This one is the least dangerous for your data, the only drawback I can think of is that you may need quite a lot storage if your database is big. But it ain&amp;rsquo;t such a big trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the biggest drawbacks of all of this, is that none of them is automatic and you can easily forget to do it once and end up with a messed up &lt;code&gt;schema.rb&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch. &lt;em&gt;Happened to me so many times before&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for us, Git gives us a way to do automated tasks whenever we change branches thanks to Git Hooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git has a way to fire off custom scripts when certain important actions occur. There are two groups of these hooks: client-side and server-side. Client-side hooks are triggered by operations such as committing and merging, while server-side hooks run on network operations such as receiving pushed commits. - &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Customizing-Git-Git-Hooks&#34; title=&#34;8.3 Customizing Git - Git Hooks&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-solution&#34;&gt;The solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking advantage of this hooks I made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/yknx4/470ec4e1378a48382fdbaf6b5896f1d0&#34;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; that automatically creates a backup of your currently active database and switch between backups whenever you switch branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL (obviously)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;psql&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;createdb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dropbp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;psql&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;createdb&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;dropdb&lt;/code&gt; are available in your path, also ensure you have a database user without password preferably named &lt;code&gt;postgres&lt;/code&gt;. (This should be the default setup in most of the development environments)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands in your projects root path  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
1.- Download the script in your project&amp;rsquo;s hooks directory and make it executable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; $ wget -O .git/hooks/post-checkout https://gist.githubusercontent.com/yknx4/470ec4e1378a48382fdbaf6b5896f1d0/raw/393a1faad80795631e08c994505f0a706404cedb/post-checkout
&amp;gt; $ chmod +x .git/hooks/post-checkout
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.- Tweak the configuration &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; $ vim .git/hooks/post-checkout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
# --- Constants
SEPARATOR=&amp;quot;/&amp;quot; # This is the separator that is going to be used to
MAIN_BACKUP=&amp;quot;_backup&amp;quot; # This is the suffix that is going to be used for a main backup
MAIN_DATABASE=&amp;quot;NAME_OF_YOUR_PROJECT_DB&amp;quot; # Here you should put the name of the db
DB_USER=&amp;quot;postgres&amp;quot; # In case your user is not postgres you may change it
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.- Thats all! You should have you database branches working now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Due to the way branch information is passed to the hook, if you create branch A and then you create another branch B without making changes and then switch back to branch B it will actually not trigger a database backup because the hook will think branch B is branch A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;some code has been trimmed to slim down the post size&lt;/em&gt;
In the first section of the script we just get the parameters received by the hook and assign them to variables, also we set the constants we are going to use throughout the script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh

# --- Command line
PREVIOUS_HEAD=&amp;quot;$1&amp;quot;
NEW_HEAD=&amp;quot;$2&amp;quot;
IS_BRANCH_CHECKOUT=&amp;quot;$3&amp;quot;

# --- Constants
SEPARATOR=&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;
MAIN_BACKUP=&amp;quot;_backup&amp;quot;
MAIN_DATABASE=&amp;quot;awesome_project_db&amp;quot;
DB_USER=&amp;quot;postgres&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I defined some functions to make the code more readable. Most of these functions receive the database name as parameter, is important to know that all the names will be trimmed to 63 characters because that is a hard limit imposed by postgres for the database names. Some really long branches names may end up with colliding backup names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# --- Functions
database_exists () {
  # logic to check if a database exists
}

kill_connections() {
  # logic to kill al the connections to the active db,
}

duplicate_database_to() {
  # logic to duplicate the main database to another one
}

drop_database() {
  # logic to drop a database
}

rename_database() {
  # logic to rename a database
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This alias makes the best guess about a branch name with the revision SHA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias branch_name=&#39;git name-rev --name-only&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I define these variables to have some useful information about git in a readable way&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# --- Variables
PREVIOUS_BRANCH=`branch_name $PREVIOUS_HEAD`
NEW_BRANCH=`git branch | grep -e &amp;quot;^*&amp;quot; | cut -d&#39; &#39; -f 2`
OLD_DATABASE=$MAIN_DATABASE$SEPARATOR$PREVIOUS_BRANCH
NEW_DATABASE=$MAIN_DATABASE$SEPARATOR$NEW_BRANCH
MAIN_BACKUP=$MAIN_DATABASE$MAIN_BACKUP
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here it comes the actual magic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# --- Script

if [ $IS_BRANCH_CHECKOUT -eq 0 ]; then
  exit 0 # Exit script if it is not a branch change
fi

echo &amp;quot;Switching from $PREVIOUS_BRANCH to $NEW_BRANCH&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;Killing existing connections to $MAIN_DATABASE&amp;quot;
kill_connections # We need to kill all the connections or the commands here will fail

if ! database_exists $MAIN_BACKUP; then
  echo &amp;quot;Creating a main backup, if something goes wrong you can manually restore from this backup.&amp;quot;
  duplicate_database_to $MAIN_BACKUP # We should always have a master backup
fi

if [ &amp;quot;$PREVIOUS_BRANCH&amp;quot; == &amp;quot;$NEW_BRANCH&amp;quot; ]; then
  exit 0 # We didn&#39;t change branch, so lets just exit
fi

if database_exists $OLD_DATABASE; then
  # We need to remove old backups if they exists (they shouldn&#39;t most of the times) but
  # sometime when we didn&#39;t had changes in the branch when we created another one, so a
  # backup for the parent branch is created instead of one for the new branch, this is
  # to delete that wrong backup.
  drop_database $OLD_DATABASE
fi

if database_exists $NEW_DATABASE; then
  # When a backup for the new branch already exists
  # If there is already a backup for the branch we are checking to, lets just rename the active database to create a new backup
  rename_database $MAIN_DATABASE $OLD_DATABASE
  # and then lets rename the existing backup to the active database name
  rename_database $NEW_DATABASE $MAIN_DATABASE
else
  # If the branch we are checking to doesn&#39;t have a backup let&#39;s just copy the db to still have an active database
  duplicate_database_to $OLD_DATABASE
fi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this is as useful as it was to me, switching to a new branch only takes about 15 seconds up from about 2 seconds, but refreshing my database from a production copy takes like 20 minutes so it&amp;rsquo;s manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me 2.0</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 10:01:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-started&#34;&gt;It started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything started before I understood what was going on. I never fitted in, &lt;strong&gt;something always felt wrong&lt;/strong&gt; and I was sure that there was something missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That started as soon as I started to know myself when I was about 5 years old. Even though I was nerdy/geekish and I always looked forward to video games, computers, etc. When it came to toys and clothes,&lt;em&gt;I always wanted the ones that wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be for boys&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-was&#34;&gt;I was&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was told at a really early age all that stuff was not for me, in a very mean way. So I never asked for it, but I craved for it. I think that&amp;rsquo;s why I never liked to get clothes as present, in comparison to now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as I grew older, I knew I was different, I knew what I wanted and it was afflicting me. &lt;em&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t know how much it can hurt you to feel you can&amp;rsquo;t be yourself&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Until I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand it anymore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day, drown in tears. I came out to the first person ever, a really close friend. I told her how I felt and what I wanted. I was scared, I thought she may think I was a weirdo, or a pervert. But she was supportive and for the first time I felt I could express myself the way I really wanted to. The same day I asked her to help me to get my very first clothes. &lt;em&gt;Feminine clothes&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Clothes that fitted my taste&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;that I always wanted to use&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about me, to be honest I&amp;rsquo;m not even that sure now, but I knew I liked girls (feminine guys worked for me too) and I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind having a kinky friend between my legs. But at the same time &lt;em&gt;I wanted to look like a girl&lt;/em&gt; and behave like one (at least most of the time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am&#34;&gt;I am&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day I know &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a transgender&lt;/em&gt;, bigender to be more precise. And to this day I also know I&amp;rsquo;m not wrong, thanks to all my close friends that have smothered me the way I am and to my lovely girlfriend that is with me in all this. Thanks to them I also know that I can be loved the same way as a any other person and I should be treated the same way too. (if you are against LGBT, this is when you can unfriend me)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope people here understand, I hope some day people all around the world will understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I want you all to know this is the real me, because I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like hiding it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll be a long way, and I&amp;rsquo;ll take baby steps. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to hide, Not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to ask me anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ale&lt;/strong&gt; Figueroa (also know as &lt;em&gt;Jorge Figueroa&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alenx&lt;/strong&gt; (also know as &lt;em&gt;yknx&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>women developers done wrong</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/women-developers-done-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 10:25:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/women-developers-done-wrong/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;women-developers-done-wrong&#34;&gt;women developers done wrong&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t take me wrong, seeking for more women in the technology world is a legit purpose and I support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fusion.net/story/115998/survey-says-92-percent-of-software-developers-are-men/&#34;&gt;92&lt;/a&gt;% of the developers are men&lt;/strong&gt;, and that&amp;rsquo;s a huge gap that makes things unfair sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But current movements are doing it wrong, sooo wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the activities that looks forward to bring more women to the developer side are like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come to the Ultrasuperduper development fair only for women&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us at the girls only programmer&amp;rsquo;s day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the women&amp;rsquo;s only developer community&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re fighting a gender polarized environment with&amp;hellip;.  Another gender polarized environment ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They want to pursue a equitable environment where there&amp;rsquo;s an equal number of men and women by making women only groups.  Doesn&amp;rsquo;t that sounds ridiculous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I think they&amp;rsquo;re taking the wrong approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll take nightclubs as example. They don&amp;rsquo;t look for the same legit purpose but have the same objective: have more women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usually there are more men than women&lt;/em&gt; in nightclubs. Why? I don&amp;rsquo;t care, but that&amp;rsquo;s a fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nightclub owners needs to have a partner for every guy in the party, so they don&amp;rsquo;t get bored and obviously to consume more drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if there more men than women looking for nightclubs, &lt;strong&gt;they need to look for strategies to get more women inside&lt;/strong&gt;. And I can assure you they will never make a girls only nightclub. That&amp;rsquo;d be stupid, and &lt;strong&gt;that&amp;rsquo;d mean wasting half of the possible customers (in our case developers).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What they do, is to make the place a little more attractive to women. Lowered prices, better seats, no cover, etc&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s not about getting rid of the males so you can get more women, is about lurking women that was not interested with attractive offers that convince them to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back in the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should try to make events attractive to women, but not limited to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about a programming course free for woman, but men for a small fee can join too. Or even  better, for a men to join he has to bring two female pals interested in learning about development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, there should be a lot of ways of making these events more interesting for women without excluding men. And that&amp;rsquo;s how it has to be done. I think this way this movements can improve a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after all, this is just my opinion. &lt;strong&gt;In a perfect world, nobody would give a f*ck if you&amp;rsquo;re men or women.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW&amp;hellip; I thought about this because recently I saw a lot of interesting development events, but they were limited to women only.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s no gender violence at all</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/theres-no-gender-violence-at-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 17:45:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/theres-no-gender-violence-at-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know today is the Women&amp;rsquo;s Day and &lt;strong&gt;this ain&amp;rsquo;t a day to celebrate but to commemorate all those women that have fought for women&amp;rsquo;s rights&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even though I agree with that, I still feel uneasy due to the fact that &lt;strong&gt;gender violence against men is usually not addressed&lt;/strong&gt;, at least not the same way and things get worse when you talk about non-traditional genders. And so sometimes I feel these kind of commemoration isn&amp;rsquo;t fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in all the flow of posts about the international women&amp;rsquo;s day I saw this pic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://yknx4.github.io/blog/images/gender_violence.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;No Gender Violence&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It says &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;there no such a thing as gender violence, gender itself is violence&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.
And then everything clicked, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt; of all gender violence is &lt;strong&gt;gender itself&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue is for boys, Pink is for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short hair for boys, Long hair for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pants for boys, Skirts for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rude for boys, Cute for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sports is for boys, Dance is for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people still live with this guidelines their lifes, even worse teach their kids that&amp;rsquo;s how they are supposed to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s the problem, since we were kids we were taught (at least that&amp;rsquo;s in Mexico) that girls have to be soft, cute, and fragile while boys have to be tough, rude, and strong. And so the stereotypes of a weak girl and a strong boy were buried on our enviroment, society, and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these were the reason 60 years ago, women were not allowed to vote, to work, to ask, to choose, to everything. And lots and lots of womens fought to overcome this, those women are the women we commemorate in this days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the same &lt;em&gt;guidelines&lt;/em&gt; removing the gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue is for persons, Pink is for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short hair for persons, Long hair for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pants for persons, Skirts for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rude for persons, Cute for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sports is for persons, Dance is for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If society lived with this, there would never be a comparison between, there would never be sterotypes, there would be only persons, no weak girls, no strong boys only persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limiting how a person is supposed to be just because of the fact that he was born with or without something between the legs it&amp;rsquo;s really stupid. And sadly these days most of this still holds true, when it cames to non cisgender persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a &lt;strong&gt;boy wants to be pretty&lt;/strong&gt;, put on makeup and wear a skirt, or a &lt;strong&gt;girl wants to look rude&lt;/strong&gt;, have short hair and wear saggy pants, &lt;strong&gt;Gender violence is still there&lt;/strong&gt;. Even when nowadays everyone is fine with girls wearing the once male-only clothes &lt;em&gt;pants&lt;/em&gt;, a boy wearing a skirt is treated as obscene, dirty, perverted, etc&amp;hellip; and I don&amp;rsquo;t see people commemorating boy&amp;rsquo;s day, or Male&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt; movement fighting for gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s stop fighting Gender Violence, and let&amp;rsquo;s figth Gender itself. We got to remove all these sterotypes. Let&amp;rsquo;s not fight for women&amp;rsquo;s rights, let&amp;rsquo;s figth for &lt;strong&gt;REAL&lt;/strong&gt; human rights. Rights that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t discriminate by sex nor gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me when i say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we get rid of Genders, we get rid of all gender issues. Including violence&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world!</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 09:19:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-this-blog&#34;&gt;About this blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is the first post, and as every programmer&amp;rsquo;s first time. It has to start with a Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a professional blogger nor a writer nor a native english speaker. Expect some idle days, expect some &lt;em&gt;unproffesional&lt;/em&gt; posts, and expect lots and lots of silly english mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;Who am i?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look the &lt;a href=&#34;//yknx4.github.io/blog/about/&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; section and &lt;a href=&#34;//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-this-and-what-this-is-not-about&#34;&gt;What is this and what this is &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; about&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may become a technology blog, this will include for sure some development posts. But after all, this is a Personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I may post about my life, my ideas, my opinions, my personal thoughts and my controverted stance on some already controverted topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to comment everything (as soon as i enable comments), I&amp;rsquo;m open to hear other&amp;rsquo;s opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And well&amp;hellip;. welcome to this place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 17:34:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-background&#34;&gt;Personal Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-myself&#34;&gt;About myself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;me&#34;&gt;me&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m Jorge Alejandro Figueroa Perez, sometimes just &lt;strong&gt;Jorge&lt;/strong&gt;, sometimes just &lt;strong&gt;Alejandro&lt;/strong&gt;, most times just &lt;a href=&#34;//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and in the Internet most of the times I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;Yknx&lt;/strong&gt; (Except on some sites where some asian dude got the nickname first).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a supporter of &lt;strong&gt;Social Freedom&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Internet Rights&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;LGBT&lt;/strong&gt; Community. I have the opinion that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;everyone can and shall live however the f*ck they want&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; as long as they don&amp;rsquo;t harm anyone else&amp;rsquo;s freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think any society should be free of oppression, and have all their human rights assured regardless of their political, religious, sexual, or whatever position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think all those rights should be also preserved and enforced in all the modern environments that are constantly surging in the Internet. (Yep, This means that you should also be able to do whatever you want on the Internet)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;against Gender Roles&lt;/em&gt; (a byproduct of sexism), I don&amp;rsquo;t think a person can be defined by what society tells them they are supposed to be just because the person was born with or without something between the legs. I consider myself &lt;a href=&#34;//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;transgender&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or even better &lt;del&gt;Allgendersatthesametime-ish&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;bigender&lt;/strong&gt;, so feel free to address me however you feel you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in this &lt;em&gt;unique&lt;/em&gt; place called &lt;strong&gt;Colima&lt;/strong&gt; in this &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt;
country called &lt;strong&gt;Mexico&lt;/strong&gt;, and I have been living here for about all my life. [Except for the 6 months I gladly had the opportunity to live in &lt;strong&gt;South Korea&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;myself&#34;&gt;myself&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to read everything about tech, and I try to hack every
single gadget in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I have a router with
tomato-wrt working as my personal server, and customized
roms on my Android devices, I also enjoy the music, and have played guitar for about 10 years, but
mostly as a casual hobby and not as a professional guitarist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Korean and Japanese culture, I had for about 5 years a University club about it, so I learned and researched a lot about it, also I lived 6 months in South Korea and been a few times too Japan. So I got to experience the real thing at least for a short time, and I came to love it even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;language-learning&#34;&gt;Language Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love languages, i really like to learn languages, as now I can handle these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;: [I&amp;rsquo;m Mexican so&amp;hellip;.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;: [Good enough for living and working - Cambride FCE B2]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Korean&lt;/strong&gt;: [Been learning for 4 years, I have a intermediate level, 난 한국말을 항상 연습 한 중인데 당신이 연습도 하고 싶으하면 매시지를 보내 주세요]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese&lt;/strong&gt;: [This is the half of my first year, so I suck pretty much :P]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;professional-background&#34;&gt;Professional Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;development&#34;&gt;Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt; student with strong Development Abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am deeply interested on mobile development for &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt;,
Desktop Applications on &lt;strong&gt;.NET&lt;/strong&gt;, and web development,
especially in newer and promising technologies like &lt;strong&gt;Nodejs&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ruby/Rails&lt;/strong&gt;, etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with programming since Secondary
School, and have tried multiple languages and platforms. So
far liking Javascript/Node.js, C#/.NET and Java/Android the
most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enviroment&#34;&gt;Enviroment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly work on &lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt; and recently &lt;strong&gt;OSX&lt;/strong&gt; but I can move freely on &lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; based
environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brackets for NodeJS and web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MacDown for Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Studio well&amp;hellip;. for Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio for .NET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyMine for Ruby (At least until I have my Student License ㅠㅠ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atom and SublimeText are my backups when something else fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;magmalabs-intern-2016-now&#34;&gt;MagmaLabs - Intern (2016 - now)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I&amp;rsquo;m doing my internship as a developer in MagmaLabs, working with Ruby/Rails, Javascript (this time AngularJS) and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beanstack (Library web application in Ruby/Rails)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MagmaRooms (Android Application for Google Calendar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;school-projects-university-of-colima-2012-2015&#34;&gt;School Projects - University of Colima (2012 - 2015)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though most school projects sucks, and we all know it, I did multiple
school projects in which I  have practiced all my learnt
knowledge. Some of them are available on my GitHub repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;information-retrieval-engine-school-project-university-of-korea-march-2016-june-2016&#34;&gt;Information Retrieval Engine (School Project) - University of Korea (March 2016 - June 2016)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had plenty of fun with this project, it was the first time i had
to work with proper Math models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to program a Information
Retrieval engine for web documents that calculates similarity
based on a query and displays relevant documents (an
archaic search engine), I did the processing in .NET and
showed the results in a web page made on Express.js/Node.js
with all the information stored in MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;education-background&#34;&gt;Education Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;8th-semester-of-bachelor-degree-in-software-engineering-university-of-colima-2012-now&#34;&gt;8th semester of Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering, University of Colima (2012- Now)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;exchange-student-program-university-of-korea-spring-semester-2015&#34;&gt;Exchange Student Program, University of Korea (Spring semester, 2015)&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>