<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transgender on [ Y k N x ]</title>
    <link>/blog/tags/transgender/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transgender on [ Y k N x ]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 10:01:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/blog/tags/transgender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>about me 2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/article/about-me-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 10:01:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/article/about-me-2.0/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-started&#34;&gt;It started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything started before I understood what was going on. I never fitted in, &lt;strong&gt;something always felt wrong&lt;/strong&gt; and I was sure that there was something missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That started as soon as I started to know myself when I was about 5 years old. Even though I was nerdy/geekish and I always looked forward to video games, computers, etc. When it came to toys and clothes,&lt;em&gt;I always wanted the ones that wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be for boys&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-was&#34;&gt;I was&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was told at a really early age all that stuff was not for me, in a very mean way. So I never asked for it, but I craved for it. I think that&amp;rsquo;s why I never liked to get clothes as present, in comparison to now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as I grew older, I knew I was different, I knew what I wanted and it was afflicting me. &lt;em&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t know how much it can hurt you to feel you can&amp;rsquo;t be yourself&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Until I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand it anymore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day, drown in tears. I came out to the first person ever, a really close friend. I told her how I felt and what I wanted. I was scared, I thought she may think I was a weirdo, or a pervert. But she was supportive and for the first time I felt I could express myself the way I really wanted to. The same day I asked her to help me to get my very first clothes. &lt;em&gt;Feminine clothes&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Clothes that fitted my taste&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;that I always wanted to use&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about me, to be honest I&amp;rsquo;m not even that sure now, but I knew I liked girls (feminine guys worked for me too) and I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind having a kinky friend between my legs. But at the same time &lt;em&gt;I wanted to look like a girl&lt;/em&gt; and behave like one (at least most of the time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am&#34;&gt;I am&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day I know &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a transgender&lt;/em&gt;, bigender to be more precise. And to this day I also know I&amp;rsquo;m not wrong, thanks to all my close friends that have smothered me the way I am and to my lovely girlfriend that is with me in all this. Thanks to them I also know that I can be loved the same way as a any other person and I should be treated the same way too. (if you are against LGBT, this is when you can unfriend me)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope people here understand, I hope some day people all around the world will understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I want you all to know this is the real me, because I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like hiding it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll be a long way, and I&amp;rsquo;ll take baby steps. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to hide, Not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to ask me anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ale&lt;/strong&gt; Figueroa (also know as &lt;em&gt;Jorge Figueroa&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alenx&lt;/strong&gt; (also know as &lt;em&gt;yknx&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s no gender violence at all</title>
      <link>/blog/article/theres-no-gender-violence-at-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 17:45:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/article/theres-no-gender-violence-at-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know today is the Women&amp;rsquo;s Day and &lt;strong&gt;this ain&amp;rsquo;t a day to celebrate but to commemorate all those women that have fought for women&amp;rsquo;s rights&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even though I agree with that, I still feel uneasy due to the fact that &lt;strong&gt;gender violence against men is usually not addressed&lt;/strong&gt;, at least not the same way and things get worse when you talk about non-traditional genders. And so sometimes I feel these kind of commemoration isn&amp;rsquo;t fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in all the flow of posts about the international women&amp;rsquo;s day I saw this pic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://yknx4.github.io/blog/images/gender_violence.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;No Gender Violence&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It says &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;there no such a thing as gender violence, gender itself is violence&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.
And then everything clicked, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt; of all gender violence is &lt;strong&gt;gender itself&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue is for boys, Pink is for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short hair for boys, Long hair for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pants for boys, Skirts for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rude for boys, Cute for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sports is for boys, Dance is for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people still live with this guidelines their lifes, even worse teach their kids that&amp;rsquo;s how they are supposed to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s the problem, since we were kids we were taught (at least that&amp;rsquo;s in Mexico) that girls have to be soft, cute, and fragile while boys have to be tough, rude, and strong. And so the stereotypes of a weak girl and a strong boy were buried on our enviroment, society, and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these were the reason 60 years ago, women were not allowed to vote, to work, to ask, to choose, to everything. And lots and lots of womens fought to overcome this, those women are the women we commemorate in this days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the same &lt;em&gt;guidelines&lt;/em&gt; removing the gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue is for persons, Pink is for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short hair for persons, Long hair for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pants for persons, Skirts for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rude for persons, Cute for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sports is for persons, Dance is for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If society lived with this, there would never be a comparison between, there would never be sterotypes, there would be only persons, no weak girls, no strong boys only persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limiting how a person is supposed to be just because of the fact that he was born with or without something between the legs it&amp;rsquo;s really stupid. And sadly these days most of this still holds true, when it cames to non cisgender persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a &lt;strong&gt;boy wants to be pretty&lt;/strong&gt;, put on makeup and wear a skirt, or a &lt;strong&gt;girl wants to look rude&lt;/strong&gt;, have short hair and wear saggy pants, &lt;strong&gt;Gender violence is still there&lt;/strong&gt;. Even when nowadays everyone is fine with girls wearing the once male-only clothes &lt;em&gt;pants&lt;/em&gt;, a boy wearing a skirt is treated as obscene, dirty, perverted, etc&amp;hellip; and I don&amp;rsquo;t see people commemorating boy&amp;rsquo;s day, or Male&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt; movement fighting for gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s stop fighting Gender Violence, and let&amp;rsquo;s figth Gender itself. We got to remove all these sterotypes. Let&amp;rsquo;s not fight for women&amp;rsquo;s rights, let&amp;rsquo;s figth for &lt;strong&gt;REAL&lt;/strong&gt; human rights. Rights that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t discriminate by sex nor gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me when i say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we get rid of Genders, we get rid of all gender issues. Including violence&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>