<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on [ Y k N x ]</title>
    <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on [ Y k N x ]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 10:01:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//yknx4.github.io/blog/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>about me 2.0</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 10:01:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-started&#34;&gt;It started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything started before I understood what was going on. I never fitted in, &lt;strong&gt;something always felt wrong&lt;/strong&gt; and I was sure that there was something missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That started as soon as I started to know myself when I was about 5 years old. Even though I was nerdy/geekish and I always looked forward to video games, computers, etc. When it came to toys and clothes,&lt;em&gt;I always wanted the ones that wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be for boys&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-was&#34;&gt;I was&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was told at a really early age all that stuff was not for me, in a very mean way. So I never asked for it, but I craved for it. I think that&amp;rsquo;s why I never liked to get clothes as present, in comparison to now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as I grew older, I knew I was different, I knew what I wanted and it was afflicting me. &lt;em&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t know how much it can hurt you to feel you can&amp;rsquo;t be yourself&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Until I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand it anymore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day, drown in tears. I came out to the first person ever, a really close friend. I told her how I felt and what I wanted. I was scared, I thought she may think I was a weirdo, or a pervert. But she was supportive and for the first time I felt I could express myself the way I really wanted to. The same day I asked her to help me to get my very first clothes. &lt;em&gt;Feminine clothes&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Clothes that fitted my taste&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;that I always wanted to use&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about me, to be honest I&amp;rsquo;m not even that sure now, but I knew I liked girls (feminine guys worked for me too) and I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind having a kinky friend between my legs. But at the same time &lt;em&gt;I wanted to look like a girl&lt;/em&gt; and behave like one (at least most of the time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am&#34;&gt;I am&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day I know &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a transgender&lt;/em&gt;, bigender to be more precise. And to this day I also know I&amp;rsquo;m not wrong, thanks to all my close friends that have smothered me the way I am and to my lovely girlfriend that is with me in all this. Thanks to them I also know that I can be loved the same way as a any other person and I should be treated the same way too. (if you are against LGBT, this is when you can unfriend me)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope people here understand, I hope some day people all around the world will understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I want you all to know this is the real me, because I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like hiding it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll be a long way, and I&amp;rsquo;ll take baby steps. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to hide, Not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to ask me anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ale&lt;/strong&gt; Figueroa (also know as &lt;em&gt;Jorge Figueroa&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alenx&lt;/strong&gt; (also know as &lt;em&gt;yknx&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world!</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 09:19:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-this-blog&#34;&gt;About this blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is the first post, and as every programmer&amp;rsquo;s first time. It has to start with a Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a professional blogger nor a writer nor a native english speaker. Expect some idle days, expect some &lt;em&gt;unproffesional&lt;/em&gt; posts, and expect lots and lots of silly english mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;Who am i?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look the &lt;a href=&#34;//yknx4.github.io/blog/about/&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; section and &lt;a href=&#34;//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/about-me-2.0/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-this-and-what-this-is-not-about&#34;&gt;What is this and what this is &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; about&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may become a technology blog, this will include for sure some development posts. But after all, this is a Personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I may post about my life, my ideas, my opinions, my personal thoughts and my controverted stance on some already controverted topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to comment everything (as soon as i enable comments), I&amp;rsquo;m open to hear other&amp;rsquo;s opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And well&amp;hellip;. welcome to this place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>