<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Movement on [ Y k N x ]</title>
    <link>blog/tags/social-movement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Movement on [ Y k N x ]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 10:25:45 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="blog/tags/social-movement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>women developers done wrong</title>
      <link>/blog/article/women-developers-done-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 10:25:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/article/women-developers-done-wrong/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;women-developers-done-wrong&#34;&gt;women developers done wrong&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t take me wrong, seeking for more women in the technology world is a legit purpose and I support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fusion.net/story/115998/survey-says-92-percent-of-software-developers-are-men/&#34;&gt;92&lt;/a&gt;% of the developers are men&lt;/strong&gt;, and that&amp;rsquo;s a huge gap that makes things unfair sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But current movements are doing it wrong, sooo wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the activities that looks forward to bring more women to the developer side are like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come to the Ultrasuperduper development fair only for women&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us at the girls only programmer&amp;rsquo;s day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the women&amp;rsquo;s only developer community&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re fighting a gender polarized environment with&amp;hellip;.  Another gender polarized environment ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They want to pursue a equitable environment where there&amp;rsquo;s an equal number of men and women by making women only groups.  Doesn&amp;rsquo;t that sounds ridiculous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I think they&amp;rsquo;re taking the wrong approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll take nightclubs as example. They don&amp;rsquo;t look for the same legit purpose but have the same objective: have more women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usually there are more men than women&lt;/em&gt; in nightclubs. Why? I don&amp;rsquo;t care, but that&amp;rsquo;s a fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nightclub owners needs to have a partner for every guy in the party, so they don&amp;rsquo;t get bored and obviously to consume more drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if there more men than women looking for nightclubs, &lt;strong&gt;they need to look for strategies to get more women inside&lt;/strong&gt;. And I can assure you they will never make a girls only nightclub. That&amp;rsquo;d be stupid, and &lt;strong&gt;that&amp;rsquo;d mean wasting half of the possible customers (in our case developers).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What they do, is to make the place a little more attractive to women. Lowered prices, better seats, no cover, etc&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s not about getting rid of the males so you can get more women, is about lurking women that was not interested with attractive offers that convince them to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back in the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should try to make events attractive to women, but not limited to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about a programming course free for woman, but men for a small fee can join too. Or even  better, for a men to join he has to bring two female pals interested in learning about development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, there should be a lot of ways of making these events more interesting for women without excluding men. And that&amp;rsquo;s how it has to be done. I think this way this movements can improve a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after all, this is just my opinion. &lt;strong&gt;In a perfect world, nobody would give a f*ck if you&amp;rsquo;re men or women.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW&amp;hellip; I thought about this because recently I saw a lot of interesting development events, but they were limited to women only.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>